<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<gcl:CodeList xmlns:gcl="http://xml.genericode.org/2004/ns/CodeList/0.2/" xmlns:doc="http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/documentation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://xml.genericode.org/2004/ns/CodeList/0.2/ CodeList.xsd">
   <Annotation>
      <Description>
         <doc:definition>Qualifies the link identifier allowing the trade to be associated with other related trades. For new implementations, the use of the "linkedTrade" element is preferred.</doc:definition>
         <doc:publicationDate>2019-03-25</doc:publicationDate>
      </Description>
   </Annotation>
   <Identification>
      <ShortName>linkTypeScheme</ShortName>
      <Version>1-0</Version>
      <CanonicalUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/link-type</CanonicalUri>
      <CanonicalVersionUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/link-type-1-0</CanonicalVersionUri>
      <LocationUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/link-type-1-0.xml</LocationUri>
   </Identification>
   <ColumnSet>
      <Column Id="Code" Use="required">
         <ShortName>Code</ShortName>
         <Data Type="token">
            <Parameter ShortName="maxLength">63</Parameter>
         </Data>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Source" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Source</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Description" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Description</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Key Id="PrimaryKey">
         <ShortName>key</ShortName>
         <ColumnRef Ref="Code"/>
      </Key>
   </ColumnSet>
   <SimpleCodeList>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>AllocatedFrom</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The trade id of the block trade that originated this trade in an allocation process. This is used by each one of the allocated trades to reference the block trade.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>AllocatedTo</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The trade id of an allocated trade. This is used by the block trade to reference the trades resulting from the allocaiton process.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>BackToBackFrom</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The trade id of a trade that this one was created to emulate the economic characteristics of. This trade is in a different legal entity from the original trade. Typically used as part of a prime brokerage, agency, or similar operation. Distinguished from MirroredFrom, in which the mirror trade is booked into the same legal entity (but a different book) than the original trade.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>BackToBackTo</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The trade id of a trade that was created to emulate the economic characteristics of this trade. This trade is in a different legal entity from the original trade. Typically used as part of a prime brokerage, agency, or similar operation. Distinguished from MirroredTo, in which the mirror trade is booked into the same legal entity (but a different book) than the original trade.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ClearedFrom</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The ID of the trade that was submitted for clearing, from which this trade was created. Equivalent to "originating trade" for a clearing operation.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ClearedTo</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The trade id of a resulting trade (beta or gamma trade) that resulted from this trade during a clearing operation. Equivalent to "resulting trade".</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CompressedFrom</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The trade id of a trade that belonged to a portfolio that this one was created to emulate the characteristics of, so that portfolio trades could be cancelled to simplify processing. Typically in compression multiple trades that are similar but not necessarily identical are emulated by a single trade or smaller number of trades that combine the risk profile of the original trade.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CompressedTo</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The trade id of a trade that emulate the characteristics of a portfolio of trades, so that portfolio trades could be cancelled to simplify processing. Typically in compression multiple trades that are similar but not necessarily identical are emulated by a single trade or smaller number of trades that combine the risk profile of the original trade.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ExercisedFrom</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The ID of an option trade that was exercised to create this trade.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ExercisedInto</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The ID of a trade that was created from this option trade when the option was exercise physically.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>MirroredFrom</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The trade id of a trade that this one was created to emulate the economic characteristics of. This trade is in then legal entity as the original trade. Typically used as part of a prime brokerage, agency, or similar operation. Distinguished from BackToBackFrom, in which the back-to-back trade is booked into a different legal entity from the original trade.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>MirroredTo</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The trade id of a trade that was created to emulate the economic characteristics of this trade. This trade is in the same legal entity as the original trade. Typically used as part of a prime brokerage, agency, or similar operation. Distinguished from BackToBackTo, in which the back-to-back trade is booked into a different legal entity from the original trade.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>NettedFrom</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The trade id of a trade that was combined with others more or less identical in characteristics, except possibly size and/or direction, into this trade. This is typically done to simplify processing.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>NettedTo</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The trade id of a trade that resulted from combinining this trade with others that were more or less identical in characteristics, except possibly size and/or direction, to simplify processing.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>NovatedFrom</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>In a novation process, the ID of the original trade that was novated to create this one.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>NovatedTo</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>In a novation process, the ID of the new trade that was created based on this one.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>RebookedFrom</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>In a cancellation-rebooking process, the previous (cancelled) version of the trade.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>RebookedTo</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>In a cancellation-rebooking process, the replacement (rebooked) version of the trade.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>StructureComponent</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Where a single, structured trade which is traded with a counterparty is decomposed into constituent trades for internal risk management, this represents the ID of the consitutent trade to which this structured trade is decomposed.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>StructureMember</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Where a series of trades are grouped into a structure for trading purposes, this represents the trade ID of another member of that structure.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>StructureParent</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Where a single, structured trade which is traded with a counterparty is decomposed into constituent trades for internal risk management, this represents the ID of the structured trade to which this consistuent trade belongs.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
   </SimpleCodeList>
</gcl:CodeList>