<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<gcl:CodeList xmlns:gcl="http://xml.genericode.org/2004/ns/CodeList/0.2/" xmlns:doc="http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/documentation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://xml.genericode.org/2004/ns/CodeList/0.2/ CodeList.xsd">
   <Annotation>
      <Description>
         <doc:definition>A simple product typology, focused on identifing the type of financial instrument, without characterizing its features.</doc:definition>
      </Description>
   </Annotation>
   <Identification>
      <ShortName>productTypeSimpleScheme</ShortName>
      <Version>1-2</Version>
      <CanonicalUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/product-type-simple</CanonicalUri>
      <CanonicalVersionUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/product-type-simple-1-2</CanonicalVersionUri>
      <LocationUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/product-type-simple-1-2.xml</LocationUri>
   </Identification>
   <ColumnSet>
      <Column Id="Code" Use="required">
         <ShortName>Code</ShortName>
         <Data Type="token">
            <Parameter ShortName="maxLength">63</Parameter>
         </Data>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Source" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Source</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Description" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Description</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Key Id="PrimaryKey">
         <ShortName>key</ShortName>
         <ColumnRef Ref="Code"/>
      </Key>
   </ColumnSet>
   <SimpleCodeList>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>InterestRateSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement which consists in swapping interest rate streams, whatever the type of interest rate references that are being used (i.e. float vs. float swaps, also known as basis swaps, are included in this category).</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>AssetSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement where one leg mimics the return of the underlying asset. No transfer of asset takes place (sometimes the sale of the bond is included in the “asset swap construct”).</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>InflationSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement where one leg references an inflation index while the other one will typically reference a variable interest rate.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CrossCurrencySwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An interest rate swap agreement which interest streams are denominated in different currencies.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party pays a periodic fee in return for a contingent payment by the other other party following a credit event on a reference entity, a specific reference obligation or a basket of such reference names.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>TotalReturnSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party transfers the economic performance of a reference asset to the other party, typically in the exchange of the financing cost of this asset.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>VarianceSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A financial derivative instrument whose price is a function of the variance of the price of the underlyer.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CapFloor</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A contract that guarantees either a maximum (cap) or a minimum (floor) level of a variable inrerest rate reference.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FRA</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Forward Rate Agreement, corresponding to an agreement between parties regarding the level of a variable interest rate at a future date.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxForward</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An agreement between two parties regarding the future value of a currency exchange rate.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A financial instrument that corresponds to the combination of an FX spot and an FX forward transactions.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>EquityOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A contract that gives the buyer of the option the right to exercise it into the equity underlyer (or its cash equivalent) under specified conditions.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>BondOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A contract that gives the buyer of the option the right to exercise it into the bond underlyer (or its cash equivalent) under specified conditions.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A contract that gives the buyer of the option the right to exercise it into the FX underlyer (or its cash equivalent) under specified conditions.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxSpot</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A foreign exchange deal that consists of a bilateral contract between a party delivering a certain amount of a currency against receiving a certain amount of another currency from a second counterparty, based on an agreed exchange rate.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxOptionStrategy</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A transaction consisting of several component transactions, at least one of which is a foreign exchange option transaction.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>BulletPayment</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Refers to one of two ways for repaying a loan; With a balloon loan, a balloon payment is paid back when the loan comes to its contractual maturity, e.g. reaches the deadline set to repayment at the time the loan was granted, representing the full loan amount (also called principal). Periodic interest payments are generally made throughout the life of the loan.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultIndex</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party pays a periodic fee in return for a contingent payment by the other party following a credit event on an Index of credit entities.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultIndexTranche</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party pays a periodic fee in return for a contingent payment by the other party following a credit event on a Tranche of an Index of credit entities.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultBasket</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party pays a periodic fee in return for a contingent payment by the other party following a credit event on a basket of credit entities.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultBasketTranche</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party pays a periodic fee in return for a contingent payment by the other party following a credit event on a Tranche of an Index of a basket of credit entities.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An option to buy protection (payer option) or sell protection (receiver option) as a credit default swap on a specific reference credit with a specific maturity.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>EquityForward</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A contract between two parties regarding the future value of the equity underlyer (or its cash equivalent).</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>InterestRateSwaption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An option to enter into an interest rate swap.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>TermDeposit</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The simple commoditized term deposit that is typically a trade with a tenor of 1-year or less with no interim interest payments.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>DividendSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>TBD</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ConvertibleBondOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An option contract in which the underlying asset is a convertible bond.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
   </SimpleCodeList>
</gcl:CodeList>