<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<gcl:CodeList xmlns:gcl="http://xml.genericode.org/2004/ns/CodeList/0.2/" xmlns:doc="http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/documentation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://xml.genericode.org/2004/ns/CodeList/0.2/ CodeList.xsd">
   <Annotation>
      <Description>
         <doc:definition>A simple product typology, focused on identifing the type of financial instrument, without characterizing its features.</doc:definition>
         <doc:publicationDate>2015-12-14</doc:publicationDate>
      </Description>
   </Annotation>
   <Identification>
      <ShortName>productTypeSimpleScheme</ShortName>
      <Version>1-5</Version>
      <CanonicalUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/product-type-simple</CanonicalUri>
      <CanonicalVersionUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/product-type-simple-1-5</CanonicalVersionUri>
      <LocationUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/product-type-simple-1-5.xml</LocationUri>
   </Identification>
   <ColumnSet>
      <Column Id="Code" Use="required">
         <ShortName>Code</ShortName>
         <Data Type="token">
            <Parameter ShortName="maxLength">63</Parameter>
         </Data>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Source" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Source</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Description" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Description</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Key Id="PrimaryKey">
         <ShortName>key</ShortName>
         <ColumnRef Ref="Code"/>
      </Key>
   </ColumnSet>
   <SimpleCodeList>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>AssetSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement where one leg mimics the return of the underlying asset. No transfer of asset takes place (sometimes the sale of the bond is included in the "asset swap construct").</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>BondOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A contract that gives the buyer of the option the right to exercise it into the bond underlyer (or its cash equivalent) under specified conditions.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>BulletPayment</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A single known payment between two parties.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>BullionForward</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An agreement between two parties to exchange at some fixed future date a given quantity of bullion for a price defined today.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CapFloor</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A contract that guarantees either a maximum (cap) or a minimum (floor) level of a variable inrerest rate reference.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CommodityOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An option on a commodity.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CommoditySwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which the payout to at least one counterparty is based on the price of a commodity or the level of a commodity index.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ConvertibleBondOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An option contract in which the underlying asset is a convertible bond.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultBasket</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party pays a periodic fee in return for a contingent payment by the other party following a credit event on a basket of credit entities.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultBasketTranche</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party pays a periodic fee in return for a contingent payment by the other party following a credit event on a Tranche of an Index of a basket of credit entities.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultIndex</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party pays a periodic fee in return for a contingent payment by the other party following a credit event on an Index of credit entities.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultIndexTranche</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party pays a periodic fee in return for a contingent payment by the other party following a credit event on a Tranche of an Index of credit entities.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An option to buy protection (payer option) or sell protection (receiver option) as a credit default swap on a specific reference credit with a specific maturity.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditDefaultSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party pays a periodic fee in return for a contingent payment by the other other party following a credit event on a reference entity, a specific reference obligation or a basket of such reference names.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CrossCurrencySwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An interest rate swap agreement which interest streams are denominated in different currencies.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>DividendSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>TBD</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>EquityForward</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A contract between two parties regarding the future value of the equity underlyer (or its cash equivalent).</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>EquityOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A contract that gives the buyer of the option the right to exercise it into the equity underlyer (or its cash equivalent) under specified conditions.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FRA</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Forward Rate Agreement, corresponding to an agreement between parties regarding the level of a variable interest rate at a future date.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxAccrualDigitalOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The holder of the option has the right to receive a fixed amount if spot at expiry is at or above (below) a pre-defined strike. The distinctive characteristic of this contract is that the Notional to be transacted at expiry is uncertain and depends on the amount of time that the underlying currency trades within a pre-set level, or levels (the "accrual barrier", or "barriers"). The total Notional is only known at the end of the accrual period, and this extra uncertainty can make an accrual option substantially cheaper than the comparable vanilla one.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxAccrualForward</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A structured forward product consisting of a single forward or a strip of forwards. For each forward, a fixed proportion of Notional is accumulated for each occasion that spot fixes within pre-defined limits (the "accrual region") - the proportion determined by the number of fixings, which may occur every business day or with some other defined frequency. The Notional does not accumulate during any period where fixings fall outside the accrual region, but resumes accruing when spot returns within the limits. At expiry, the accrued Notional is bought at the pre-agreed hedge rate (the "strike" rate).</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxAccrualOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A financial contract between two parties (the buyer and the seller) that provides the buyer the right to buy a currency (or receive a payment) at expiry. The distinctive characteristic of this contract is that the Notional to be transacted at expiry is uncertain and depends on the amount of time that the underlying currency trades within a pre-set level, or levels (the "accrual barrier", or "barriers"). The total Notional is only known at the end of the accrual period, and this extra uncertainty can make an accrual option substantially cheaper than the comparable vanilla one.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxForward</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An agreement between two parties regarding the future value of a currency exchange rate.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxForwardVolatilityAgreement</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A contract on future levels of implied volatility. This contract can be cash settled or physically delivered.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxNonDeliverableForward</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A cash-settled agreement between two parties regarding the future value of a currency exchange rate.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxOption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A contract that gives the buyer of the option the right to exercise it into the FX underlyer (or its cash equivalent) under specified conditions.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxOptionStrategy</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A transaction consisting of several component transactions, at least one of which is a foreign exchange option transaction.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxRangeAccrual</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The holder of the option has the right to receive a pre-defined amount for every day (or pre-defined frequency) that spot trades within the accrual range. The distinctive characteristic of this contract is that the Notional to be transacted at expiry is uncertain and depends on the amount of time that the underlying currency trades within a pre-set level, or levels (the "accrual barrier", or "barriers"). The total Notional is only known at the end of the accrual period, and this extra uncertainty can make an accrual option substantially cheaper than the comparable vanilla one.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxSpot</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A foreign exchange deal that consists of a bilateral contract between a party delivering a certain amount of a currency against receiving a certain amount of another currency from a second counterparty, based on an agreed exchange rate.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A financial instrument that corresponds to the combination of an FX spot and an FX forward transactions.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxTarget</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A structured forward product which consists of a strip of forwards. Each forward may be settled as an exchange of currencies or cash settled. At each settlement, the amount of gain that one party achieves is measured. The product has a target level of gain. Once the accumulated gain exceeds the target level, the product terminates/knocks out and there are no further settlements.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxVarianceSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A Non-Deliverable Swap FX transaction that monitors the difference between the realized Variance and a fixed Variance rate of an underlying currency pair determined upon trade inception.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FxVolatilitySwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A Non-Deliverable Swap FX transaction that monitors the difference between the realized Volatility and a fixed Volatility rate of an underlying currency pair determined upon trade inception.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>InflationSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement where one leg references an inflation index while the other one will typically reference a variable interest rate.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>InterestRateSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement which consists in swapping interest rate streams, whatever the type of interest rate references that are being used (i.e. float vs. float swaps, also known as basis swaps, are included in this category).</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>InterestRateSwaption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An option to enter into an interest rate swap.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>TermDeposit</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The simple commoditized term deposit that is typically a trade with a tenor of 1-year or less with no interim interest payments.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>TotalReturnSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A swap agreement in which one party transfers the economic performance of a reference asset to the other party, typically in the exchange of the financing cost of this asset.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>VarianceSwap</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A financial derivative instrument whose price is a function of the variance of the price of the underlyer.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
   </SimpleCodeList>
</gcl:CodeList>