<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="FpML.CodeList.genericode.css"?>
<gcl:CodeList xmlns:gcl="https://docs.oasis-open.org/codelist/ns/genericode/1.0/" xmlns:doc="http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/documentation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://docs.oasis-open.org/codelist/ns/genericode/1.0/ genericode.xsd">
   <Annotation>
      <Description>
         <doc:definition>Defines a scheme of values for specifying the type of corporate
            action.</doc:definition>
         <doc:publicationDate>2013-07-26</doc:publicationDate>
      </Description>
   </Annotation>
   <Identification>
      <ShortName>corporateActionScheme</ShortName>
      <Version>1-1</Version>
      <CanonicalUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/corporate-action</CanonicalUri>
      <CanonicalVersionUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/corporate-action-1-1</CanonicalVersionUri>
      <LocationUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/corporate-action-1-1.xml</LocationUri>
   </Identification>
   <ColumnSet>
      <Column Id="Code" Use="required">
         <ShortName>Code</ShortName>
         <Data Type="token">
            <Parameter ShortName="maxLength">63</Parameter>
         </Data>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Source" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Source</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Description" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Description</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Key Id="PrimaryKey">
         <ShortName>key</ShortName>
         <ColumnRef Ref="Code"/>
      </Key>
   </ColumnSet>
   <SimpleCodeList>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Bankruptcy</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by bankruptcy. A legal proceeding involving a
                    person or business that is unable to repay outstanding debts. The bankruptcy
                    process begins with a petition filed by the debtor (most common) or on behalf of
                    creditors (less common). All of the debtor's assets are measured and evaluated,
                    whereupon the assets are used to repay a portion of outstanding debt. Upon the
                    successful completion of bankruptcy proceedings, the debtor is relieved of the
                    debt obligations incurred prior to filing for bankruptcy. The value maps closely
                    to the ISO code (BRUP) defined as the legal status of a company unable to pay
                    creditors. Bankruptcy usually involves a formal court ruling. Securities may
                    become valueless.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>BonusIssue</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by a bonus issue. A bonus issue or bonus share
                    is a free share of stock given to current shareholders in a company, based upon
                    the number of shares that the shareholder already owns. While the issue of bonus
                    shares increases the total number of shares issued and owned, it does not change
                    the value of the company. The value maps closely to the ISO code (BONU) defined
                    as a bonus, scrip or capitalisation issue. Security holders receive additional
                    assets free of payment from the issuer, in proportion to their
                    holding.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ClassAction</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by a Class Action. An action where an
                    individual represents a group in a court claim. The judgment from the suit is
                    for all the members of the group (class). The value maps closely to the ISO code
                    (CLSA) defined as the situation where interested parties seek restitution for
                    financial loss. The security holder may be offered the opportunity to join a
                    class action proceeding and would need to respond with an
                    instruction.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>CreditEvent</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by a credit event. A credit event is any
                    sudden and tangible (negative) change in a borrower's credit standing or decline
                    in credit rating. A credit event brings into question the borrower's ability to
                    repay its debt. It is the defining trigger in a credit derivative contract, or
                    credit default swap. If the borrower experiences a credit event, then the buyer
                    of the contract must pay the seller an agreed-upon sum to cover the loss. The
                    value maps closely to the ISO code (CREV) defined as an occurrence of credit
                    derivative for which the issuer of one or several underlying securities is
                    unable to fulfill his financial obligations (as defined in terms and
                    conditions).</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Default</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by a default. The failure to promptly pay
                    interest or principal when due. Default occurs when a debtor is unable to meet
                    the legal obligation of debt repayment. Borrowers may default when they are
                    unable to make the required payment or are unwilling to honor the debt. The
                    value maps closely to the ISO code (DFLT) defined as the failure by the company
                    to perform obligations defined as default events under the bond agreement and
                    that have not been remedied.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>EarlyRedemption</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by an early redemption. The value maps closely
                    to the ISO code (MCAL) defined as the redemption of an entire issue outstanding
                    of securities, for example, bonds, preferred equity, funds, by the issuer or its
                    agent, for example, asset manager, before final maturity.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>EquityRights</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by Equity Rights.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Liquidation</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by a liquidation. When a business or firm is
                    terminated or bankrupt, its assets are sold (liquidated) and the proceeds pay
                    creditors. Any leftovers are distributed to shareholders. The value maps closely
                    to the ISO code (LIQU) defined as a distribution of cash, assets or both. Debt
                    may be paid in order of priority based on preferred claims to assets specified
                    by the security.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Merger</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by a merger. Mergers and acquisitions
                    (abbreviated M&amp;A) is an aspect of corporate strategy, corporate finance
                    and management dealing with the buying, selling, dividing and combining of
                    different companies and similar entities that can help an enterprise grow
                    rapidly in its sector or location of origin, or a new field or new location,
                    without creating a subsidiary, other child entity or using a joint venture. The
                    distinction between a "merger" and an "acquisition" has become increasingly
                    blurred in various respects (particularly in terms of the ultimate economic
                    outcome), although it has not completely disappeared in all situations. The
                    value maps closely to the ISO code (MRGR) defined as an offer made to
                    shareholders, normally by a third party, requesting them to sell (tender) or
                    exchange their equities.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ReverseSplit</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by a reverse split. A reverse stock split or
                    reverse split is a process by a company of issuing to each shareholder in that
                    company a smaller number of new shares in proportion to that shareholder's
                    original shares that are subsequently canceled. A reverse stock split is also
                    called a stock merge. The reduction in the number of issued shares is
                    accompanied by a proportional increase in the share price. The value maps
                    closely to the ISO code (SPLR) defined as a decrease in a company's number of
                    outstanding equities without any change in the shareholder's equity or the
                    aggregate market value at the time of the split. Equity price and nominal value
                    are increased accordingly.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>SpinOff</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by a spin Off. A spin-out, also known as a
                    spin-off or a starburst, refers to a type of corporate action where a company
                    "splits off" sections of itself as a separate business. The value maps closely
                    to the ISO code (SOFF) defined as a a distribution of subsidiary stock to the
                    shareholders of the parent company without a surrender of shares. Spin-off
                    represents a form of divestiture usually resulting in an independent company or
                    in an existing company. For example, demerger, distribution,
                    unbundling.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>StockReclassification</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by a Stock Reclassification.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>StockSplit</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by a stock split. A stock split or stock
                    divide increases the number of shares in a public company. The price is adjusted
                    such that the before and after market capitalization of the company remains the
                    same and dilutiondoes not occur. The value maps closely to the ISO code (SPLF)
                    defined as a distribution of subsidiary stock to the shareholders of the parent
                    company without a surrender of shares. Spin-off represents a form of divestiture
                    usually resulting in an independent company or in an existing company. For
                    example, demerger, distribution, unbundling.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Takeover</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corporate action triggered by a takeover. A takeover is the purchase of
                    onecompany (the target) by another (the acquirer, or bidder). The value maps to
                    the ISO code (TEND) but is finer grained than TEND which emcompasses
                    Tender/Acquisition/Takeover/Purchase Offer/Buyback. ISO defines the TEND code as
                    an offer made to shareholders, normally by a third party, requesting them to
                    sell (tender) or exchange their equities.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
   </SimpleCodeList>
</gcl:CodeList>