<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="FpML.CodeList.genericode.css"?>
<gcl:CodeList xmlns:gcl="https://docs.oasis-open.org/codelist/ns/genericode/1.0/" xmlns:doc="http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/documentation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://docs.oasis-open.org/codelist/ns/genericode/1.0/ genericode.xsd">
   <Annotation>
      <Description>
         <doc:definition>Defines a scheme of values for specifying the type of credit
            event.</doc:definition>
         <doc:publicationDate>2022-11-18</doc:publicationDate>
      </Description>
   </Annotation>
   <Identification>
      <ShortName>creditEventTypeScheme</ShortName>
      <Version>1.0</Version>
      <CanonicalUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/credit-event-type</CanonicalUri>
      <CanonicalVersionUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/credit-event-type-1-0</CanonicalVersionUri>
      <LocationUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/credit-event-type-1-0.xml</LocationUri>
   </Identification>
   <ColumnSet>
      <Column Id="Code" Use="required">
         <ShortName>Code</ShortName>
         <Data Type="token">
            <Parameter ShortName="maxLength">63</Parameter>
         </Data>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Source" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Source</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Description" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Description</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Key Id="PrimaryKey">
         <ShortName>key</ShortName>
         <ColumnRef Ref="Code"/>
      </Key>
   </ColumnSet>
   <SimpleCodeList>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Bankruptcy</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The reference entity has been dissolved or has become insolvent. It also
                    covers events that may be a precursor to insolvency such as instigation of
                    bankruptcy or insolvency proceedings. Sovereign trades are not subject to
                    Bankruptcy as "technically" a Sovereign cannot become bankrupt. ISDA 2003 Term:
                    Bankruptcy.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>DistressedRatingsDowngrade</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Results from the fact that the rating of the reference obligation is
                    downgraded to a distressed rating level. From a usage standpoint, this credit
                    event is typically not applicable in case of RMBS trades.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FailureToPay</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>This credit event triggers, after the expiration of any applicable grace
                    period, if the reference entity fails to make due payments in an aggregrate
                    amount of not less than the payment requirement on one or more obligations (e.g.
                    a missed coupon payment). ISDA 2003 Term: Failure to Pay.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FailureToPayInterest</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corresponds to the failure by the Reference Entity to pay an expected
                    interest amount or the payment of an actual interest amount that is less than
                    the expected interest amount. ISDA 2003 Term: Failure to Pay
                    Interest.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FailureToPayPrincipal</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Corresponds to the failure by the Reference Entity to pay an expected
                    principal amount or the payment of an actual principal amount that is less than
                    the expected principal amount. ISDA 2003 Term: Failure to Pay
                    Principal.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>GovernmentalIntervention</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A governmental intervention is an event resulting from an action by a
                    governmental authority that materially impacts the reference entity's
                    obligations, such as an interest rate reduction, principal reduction, deferral
                    of interest or principal, change in priority ranking, or change in currency or
                    composition of payment. ISDA 2014 Term: Governmental Intervention.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ImpliedWritedown</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Results from the fact that losses occur to the underlying instruments
                    that do not result in reductions of the outstanding principal of the reference
                    obligation.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>MaturityExtension</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Results from the fact that the underlier fails to make principal payments
                    as expected.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ObligationAcceleration</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>One or more of the obligations have been declared due and payable before
                    they would otherwise have been due and payable as a result of, or on the basis
                    of, the occurrence of a default, event of default or other similar condition or
                    event other than failure to pay (preferred by the market over Obligation
                    Default, because more definitive and encompasses the definition of Obligation
                    Default - this is more favorable to the Seller). Subject to the default
                    requirement amount. ISDA 2003 Term: Obligation Acceleration.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ObligationDefault</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>One or more of the obligations have become capable of being declared due
                    and payable before they would otherwise have been due and payable as a result
                    of, or on the basis of, the occurrence of a default, event of default or other
                    similar condition or event other than failure to pay. ISDA 2003 Term: Obligation
                    Default.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>RepudiationMoratorium</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>The reference entity, or a governmental authority, either refuses to
                    recognise or challenges the validity of one or more obligations of the reference
                    entity, or imposes a moratorium thereby postponing payments on one or more of
                    the obligations of the reference entity. Subject to the default requirement
                    amount. ISDA 2003 Term: Repudiation/Moratorium.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Restructuring</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A restructuring is an event that materially impacts the reference
                    entity's obligations, such as an interest rate reduction, principal reduction,
                    deferral of interest or principal, change in priority ranking, or change in
                    currency or composition of payment. ISDA 2003 Term: Restructuring.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Writedown</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Results from the fact that the underlier writes down its outstanding
                    principal amount.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
   </SimpleCodeList>
</gcl:CodeList>