<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="FpML.CodeList.genericode.css"?>
<gcl:CodeList xmlns:gcl="https://docs.oasis-open.org/codelist/ns/genericode/1.0/" xmlns:doc="http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/documentation" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://docs.oasis-open.org/codelist/ns/genericode/1.0/ genericode.xsd">
   <Annotation>
      <Description>
         <doc:definition>Various features associated with a given facility.</doc:definition>
         <doc:publicationDate>2019-10-31</doc:publicationDate>
      </Description>
   </Annotation>
   <Identification>
      <ShortName>facilityFeatureScheme</ShortName>
      <Version>1-1</Version>
      <CanonicalUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/facility-feature</CanonicalUri>
      <CanonicalVersionUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/facility-feature-1-1</CanonicalVersionUri>
      <LocationUri>http://www.fpml.org/coding-scheme/facility-feature-1-1.xml</LocationUri>
   </Identification>
   <ColumnSet>
      <Column Id="Code" Use="required">
         <ShortName>Code</ShortName>
         <Data Type="token">
            <Parameter ShortName="maxLength">63</Parameter>
         </Data>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Source" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Source</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Column Id="Description" Use="optional">
         <ShortName>Description</ShortName>
         <Data Type="string"/>
      </Column>
      <Key Id="PrimaryKey">
         <ShortName>key</ShortName>
         <ColumnRef Ref="Code"/>
      </Key>
   </ColumnSet>
   <SimpleCodeList>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>ABL</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Asset -Based Loan (ABL): a loan that is secured by specific assets
                    (typically receivables or inventory) an made on the basis of a borrowing formula
                    (borrowing base) that reflects a percentage of the value of such
                    assets.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Acquisition</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A specific type of loan that typically cannot be reborrowed. Funds can be
                    drawn down from the line of credit only for a specific period of time and only
                    to purchase specified assets.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Add-On</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An increase to an existing facility.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Advance</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An individual borrowing under a credit facility.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>BankersAcceptance</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A promised future payment, or time draft, which is accepted and
                    guaranteed by a bank and drawn on a deposit at the bank. The banker's acceptance
                    specifies the amount of money, the date, and the person to which the payment is
                    due. After acceptance, the draft becomes an unconditional liability of the bank.
                    But the holder of the draft can sell (exchange) it for cash at a discount to a
                    buyer who is willing to wait until the maturity date for the funds in the
                    deposit.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Bridge</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A Credit Facility pursuant to which Lenders make Bridge Loans which are
                    short-term loans (generally maturing in one year) that typically (although not
                    always) are not intended to be funded. The purpose of the Bridge Loan is to
                    provide a bidder with a committed financing in the context of an action for a
                    business in case the Notes offering contemplated as part of the acquisition
                    financing cannot be consummated prior to the consumption of the acquisition
                    (i.e., to "bridge" the gap in financing). Traditionally, Bridge Loans are used
                    by Financial Buyers (Sponsors) in auction situations, but corporate buyers also
                    sometimes use Bridge Loans to finance acquisitions. </SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Capex</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A facility whose loans are used to fund capital expenditures which are
                    defined as any expenditure in respect of a capital asset of the borrower, i.e.,
                    an expenditure that does not flow through the borrower's income
                    statement.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>DIP</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Debtor-In-Possession (DIP Loan Facility: A credit agreement entered into
                    by a borrower during the course of its Chapter 11 bankruptcy case, which is
                    secured and has priority over existing debt and other claims. </SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Exit</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Financing that takes place when a debtor is ready to confirm a plan and
                    exit Bankruptcy. It is through Exit Financing that the debtor is able to fund
                    its plan of reorganization. In most, if not all, plans of reorganization, Exit
                    Financing is required to be available before a debtor can reach the effective
                    date for its plan. </SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Extended</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Credit Facility that is extended beyond its original maturity date. When
                    all or a portion of the initial facilitiy remains and is not extended, the
                    extended portion becomes a new facility. </SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Guarantee</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A Guarantor's agreement to purchase or otherwise become contingently
                    liable for the debts or other obligations of another entity. With respect to a
                    group of companies guarantees can be "upstream" (a subsidiary guaranteeing debt
                    of its parent), "cross-stream" (a subsidiary guaranteeing debt of a "sister"
                    company, where both are ultimately owned by the same parent) and "downstream" (a
                    parent guaranteeing debt of a subsidiary).</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Incremental</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A post-Closing addition to an existing Credit Facility on substantially
                    the same terms as the existing Credit Facility, typically used to finance
                    acquisitions, investments or even dividends. The existing Lenders do not
                    precommit to provide the Incremental Facility, but do pre-approve the
                    incremental leverage. At the time the Borrower desires to add on to the existing
                    Credit Facility, it must seek new commitments from existing or new Lenders.
                    Incremental Facility debt is additional Secured Debt that shares Collateral with
                    the pre-existing First or Second Lien Debt. </SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Mezzanine</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An unsecured debt instrument with certain equity-like characteristics.
                    The Mezzanine component of a capital structure is subordinate in right of
                    payment to Senior Debt and carries a coupon similar to high yield bonds.
                    Mezzanine debt is often issued at the holdco level. Mezzanine debt often has
                    equity features, frequently referred to as equity kickers, which may take the
                    form of warrants that permit the holder to purchase equity at a preset price, or
                    conversion features upon certain events (such as change of control). The
                    combination of the debt coupon and the equity kicker gives Mezzanine investors a
                    higher return than high yield bonds. </SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Non-Extended</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Credit Facility that is not extended beyond its original maturity
                    date.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>PIK</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>"Payment in Kind" interest is a form of payment where the interest owed
                    by the borrower is added to the principal amount owed to a lender. A separate
                    PIK facility is comprised of this interest.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>PIKToggle</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>An interest rate feature that gives the Borrower the option to pay all,
                    half or none of the interest for any period (generally during a non-call period)
                    in kind. Typically, an interest rate step up will apply to any portion of
                    interest that is paid in kind. PIK Toggles are attractive to Borrowers because
                    of the ability to "toggle" out of cash interest payments in times of a liquidity
                    crunch - meaning if the Borrower is short on cash, it can stop making cash
                    interest payments and just let the interest PIK.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Synthetic</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Typically refers to letters of credit.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
      <Row>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>Unitranche</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>FpML</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
         <Value>
            <SimpleValue>A hybrid loan facility structure that combines senior debt and
                    subordinated debt into one facility bearing a blended interest rate. This type
                    of financing is mainly aimed at middle market companies and used by private
                    equity in leveraged buyouts.</SimpleValue>
         </Value>
      </Row>
   </SimpleCodeList>
</gcl:CodeList>